<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SLU SOC 4650 and 5650</title>
    <link>https://slu-soc5650.github.io/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://slu-soc5650.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>SLU SOC 4650 and 5650</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2017-2021 Christopher G. Prener</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 00:00:00 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://slu-soc5650.github.io/images/icon_hu137d436a85c84cab921c9c47edaed5ef_12382_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>SLU SOC 4650 and 5650</title>
      <link>https://slu-soc5650.github.io/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting 03 - Cartography 101</title>
      <link>https://slu-soc5650.github.io/docs/meeting_03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://slu-soc5650.github.io/docs/meeting_03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;br&gt; 
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-warning&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Please submit Lab-02 on your own via GitHub Desktop!
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;meeting-goals&#34;&gt;Meeting Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This course meeting has an emphasis on the following goals:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apply gestalt principles to map reading and map design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Design &lt;code&gt;ggplot2&lt;/code&gt; maps with both figure and ground layers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Revise &lt;code&gt;ggplot2&lt;/code&gt; maps to use different color ramps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Employ different break algorithms to &amp;ldquo;bin&amp;rdquo; data together on a map&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;before-class&#34;&gt;Before Class&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;tasks&#34;&gt;Tasks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please complete the tasks listed on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://slu-soc5650.github.io/syllabus/module-1-course-introduction.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;syllabus&lt;/a&gt;, and see &lt;a href=&#34;https://blackboard.slu.edu&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Blackboard&lt;/a&gt; for the entry ticket link.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;during-class&#34;&gt;During Class&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;agenda&#34;&gt;Agenda&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exercise 1 - Discussing Map Layers and Cartographic Choices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exercise 2 - Complicating Our &lt;code&gt;ggplot2&lt;/code&gt; Maps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Break&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lab-02 and one-on-one meetings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;exercise-1---discussing-map-layers-and-cartographic-choices&#34;&gt;Exercise 1 - Discussing Map Layers and Cartographic Choices&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To illustrate some of the points about gestalt principles and color in the meeting prep video, please consider the following questions as a group after taking a look at this &lt;a href=&#34;http://npmaps.com/wp-content/uploads/ozark-map.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;map of Ozark National Senic Riverways&lt;/a&gt;, a National Park Service resource in southern Missouri.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What do you think are the ground layers?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What do you think are the figure layers?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How is the gestalt principle of nearness used?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How is the gestalt principle of similarity used?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What do you think is the hierarchical organization of layers?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;exercise-2---complicating-our-ggplot2-maps&#34;&gt;Exercise 2 - Complicating Our ggplot2 Maps&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To apply some of our gestalt principles, and also introduce some tools for working with color, we&amp;rsquo;re going to add some complexity to the way we&amp;rsquo;re been using &lt;code&gt;ggplot2&lt;/code&gt; for mapping. Our goal is to load some data saved in several shapefiles and then:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a map using &lt;code&gt;ggplot()&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;em&gt;several instances&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;geom_sf()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manually alter color of layers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Illustrate using &lt;code&gt;viridis&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;RColorBrewer&lt;/code&gt; to create palettes for thematic maps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use a custom function to create map breaks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of the materials are available in our &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/slu-soc5650/module-1-cartography&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;meeting GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;after-class&#34;&gt;After Class&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lab-03 instructions are available in &lt;code&gt;module-1-cartography&lt;/code&gt; or can viewed online &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/slu-soc5650/module-1-cartography/blob/master/assignments/lab-03.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. You&amp;rsquo;ll need to create a new &lt;code&gt;.Rproj&lt;/code&gt; for it in your assignments repository and then create a static map of St. Louis showing the percentage of people living in poverty. This map should include the Mississippi River and local highways as ground layers, and include map breaks as well as a &lt;code&gt;viridis&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;RColorBrewer&lt;/code&gt; palette of your choice.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Final Project Notes</title>
      <link>https://slu-soc5650.github.io/docs/final_project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://slu-soc5650.github.io/docs/final_project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we go through the semester, I&amp;rsquo;ll be using this section to add some additional information about the final project. For now, you can find the deadlines associated with the project on &lt;a href=&#34;https://slu-soc5650.github.io/syllabus/assignments.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;our syllabus&lt;/a&gt; and steps for the initial vignettes in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://slu-soc5650.github.io/final-project/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;final project instructions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting 02 - Map Production Basics</title>
      <link>https://slu-soc5650.github.io/docs/meeting_02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://slu-soc5650.github.io/docs/meeting_02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;br&gt; 
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-warning&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Please come to class with your Lab-01 materials ready to submit!
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;meeting-goals&#34;&gt;Meeting Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This course meeting has an emphasis on the following goals:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduce &lt;code&gt;ggplot2&lt;/code&gt; for static mapping in &lt;code&gt;R&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduce Git and GitHub for analysis development&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Distinguish between different scales of maps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evaluate the effect that normalizing data has on a map&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;before-class&#34;&gt;Before Class&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;tasks&#34;&gt;Tasks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Double-check to make sure you have completed all course onboarding steps (see Blackboard)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Complete Lab-01 from our first course meeting, and come prepared to submit it during class&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Complete the two meeting prep videos (see Blackboard)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Submit Entry Ticket 02 (see Blackboard)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Submit your final project memo (see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://slu-soc5650.github.io/final-project/topic-data-selection.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;final project instructions&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;during-class&#34;&gt;During Class&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;agenda&#34;&gt;Agenda&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exercise 1 - Discussing Map Scale and Features&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exercise 2 - Working with Git and GitHub&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Break&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exercise 3 - Introducing &lt;code&gt;ggplot2&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Break&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lab-02 and one-on-one meetings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;exercise-1---discussing-map-scale-and-features&#34;&gt;Exercise 1 - Discussing Map Scale and Features&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To illustrate some of the points about scale and detail in the second meeting prep video, we&amp;rsquo;ll take a look at some maps of California from a number of different sources. The goal is to get more comfortable talking and thinking about maps, their purpose, and you need to make them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Map 1 - &lt;a href=&#34;http://npmaps.com/wp-content/uploads/yosemite-valley-map.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Yosemite Valley Detail Map&lt;/a&gt; via the National Park Service / npmaps.com&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Map 2 - &lt;a href=&#34;https://prd-tnm.s3.amazonaws.com/StagedProducts/Maps/USTopo/PDF/CA/CA_Tenaya_Lake_20150226_TM_geo.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Tenaya Lake 2015 7.5 Minute Topo Map&lt;/a&gt; via pickatrail.com&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Map 3 - &lt;a href=&#34;http://npmaps.com/wp-content/uploads/yosemite-map.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Main Yosemite National Park Map&lt;/a&gt; via the National Park Service / npmaps.com&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Map 4 - &lt;a href=&#34;https://slu-soc5650.github.io/module-1-basics/results/california_total_population.png&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Map of California Counties by Population, Count&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Map 5 - &lt;a href=&#34;https://slu-soc5650.github.io/module-1-basics/results/california_population_density.png&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Map of California Counties by Population, Density&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For these maps, discuss the following four questions in your breakout groups:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The scale that they are mapped at - which is the largest scale map? Which is the smallest scale map? How do the ones in between differ?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the relationship between scale and what you think the intended use of each map might be?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What data and &amp;ldquo;layers&amp;rdquo; are needed for each of the maps? For different data, think about whether they are points, lines, or polygons.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Which map, Map 4 or Map 5, is properly normalized? What is the effect of normalization?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;exercise-2---working-with-git-and-github&#34;&gt;Exercise 2 - Working with Git and GitHub&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since we&amp;rsquo;ll be submitting our work through GitHub this semester, the goal of this exercise is to get comfortable with the GitHub Desktop user interface as well as the Git workflow that we discussed in the first meeting prep video this week. We&amp;rsquo;ll talk about GitHub Desktop, and then work through three examples of the workflow:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clone the &lt;code&gt;module-1-basics&lt;/code&gt; repo with today&amp;rsquo;s meeting materials&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clone your assignment repo, add &lt;code&gt;Lab-01&lt;/code&gt;, commit the changes, and submit it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clone your final project repo, add a &lt;code&gt;.Rproj&lt;/code&gt; project file to it, and submit it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;exercise-3---introducing-ggplot2&#34;&gt;Exercise 3 - Introducing ggplot2&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ll be using &lt;code&gt;ggplot2&lt;/code&gt; this semester to produce static thematic maps in &lt;code&gt;R&lt;/code&gt;. To get acquainted with &lt;code&gt;ggplot2&lt;/code&gt;, we&amp;rsquo;ll re-create Maps 4 and 5 above. All of the materials are available in our &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/slu-soc5650/module-1-basics&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;meeting GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;. Our goal is to load some data saved in a shapefile (review from last week) and then:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a map using &lt;code&gt;ggplot()&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;geom_sf()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add a color &lt;code&gt;viridis&lt;/code&gt; color palette to the map&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add a title, subtitle, and caption to the map&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;after-class&#34;&gt;After Class&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;tasks-1&#34;&gt;Tasks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Complete Lab-02 after and &lt;em&gt;try to submit it via GitHub on your own&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Follow-up with Chris in your Final Project repo about any outstanding memo questions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;lab-02&#34;&gt;Lab-02&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lab-02 instructions are available in &lt;code&gt;module-1-basics&lt;/code&gt; or can viewed online &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/slu-soc5650/module-1-basics/blob/master/assignments/lab-02.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. You&amp;rsquo;ll need to create a new &lt;code&gt;.Rproj&lt;/code&gt; for it in your assignments repository (which you cloned during class), and then create a static map using &lt;code&gt;ggplot2&lt;/code&gt; of Missouri counties&#39; total populations that is appropriately normalized.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Pandemic - Plans for Remote Learning</title>
      <link>https://slu-soc5650.github.io/covid19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://slu-soc5650.github.io/covid19/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re once again facing a semester dramatically altered by our public health situation, though with both more risk (in the form of mutations to the SARS-CoV-2 virus that causes COVID-19) and more hope (in the form of vaccines). Like last semester, this means we are starting another semester with what feel like novel questions. Will social distancing requirements be relaxed at any point before May? When will we be able to get vaccinated? What happens if we get sick before we can get a shot? If this is your first semester at SLU, you probably have even more questions about starting at a new institution in the middle of a pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been reflecting this summer about how novel this all still feels even though we are nearly ten months into this odyssey. I suspect, though, that the Billikens who arrived on campus in the fall of 1918 had similar questions. SLU turned 100 years old that year, and despite the pandemic, we&amp;rsquo;re still around, having just celebrated the completion of our bicentennial. I share this to say - we&amp;rsquo;ll get through this, just like the classes of 1919, 1920, 1921, and 1922 did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My goal for this page is to clarify, at least for the context of my SOC 1120 sections, what this course will be like this semester as we navigate our &amp;ldquo;new normal.&amp;rdquo; I hope doing so reduces some of the ambiguity and stress related to this class and your fall semesters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;focusing-on-what-matters&#34;&gt;Focusing on What Matters&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, though, I think it is important to acknowledge the current situation we are all collectively facing outside of coursework. I assume that all of us are worried about lots of other things, too. You may be wondering if we&amp;rsquo;ll have to leave campus at some point this semester, or if you or your friends or your family will get sick. Millions of Americans, including perhaps you or some of your family members, are struggling financially because of the economic consequences of this virus. Perhaps you are worried about what will happen to them if you are focused on classes? Or how you will focus on classes while also helping them?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In March, our lives were dramatically disrupted almost overnight. My wife and I had to worry about what would happen to our daughter if we both got sick. Or if we would see our family, who all live far from Missouri, ever again. Fortunately we did not get sick last spring, and we got to see our families this past summer and fall. Now, however, we have new concerns, like being back in St. Louis away from our families again, and what 2021 will bring with new variants of COVID and vaccination. We should be honest with ourselves - this is an incredibly significant, stressful, and life-altering event we are all collectively experiencing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All of this takes precedence over a semester&amp;rsquo;s worth of college or graduate school classes.&lt;/strong&gt; I want to make clear that we should not and cannot continue with coursework as if things are &amp;ldquo;normal.&amp;rdquo; We can&amp;rsquo;t ignore the fact that we are living in a moment of uncertainty and crisis. This means we have to be kind to ourselves and each other. It also means all of us, but especially faculty, need drastically re-calibrate our expectations for what we will learn and achieve in courses this semester. This is important because (1) it&amp;rsquo;s just true (2) our mental health will suffer if we don&amp;rsquo;t acknowledge this and try to go on as if everything is normal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;practice-self-care&#34;&gt;Practice Self Care&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing all of you should do is think about what you need to do for yourselves this semester. I exercise a lot - mostly running outdoors when it is nice and cycling indoors when the weather isn&amp;rsquo;t great. I meditate. I have a set daily schedule that I follow even though I&amp;rsquo;m home. I try to make time to read for pleasure. And I write (ok, vent!) about what is going on each day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of this may be useful to you, and some of it might not be. You need to find what works for you. The fourth part of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sites.google.com/slu.edu/covid-19fall2020preparationmod/home/part-four-encouragement-and-support&#34; target = &#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Return to Campus Module&lt;/a&gt; provides some suggestions for getting encouragement and support. Please return to that for advice, or feel free to talk to me about strategies you can use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-class-will-be-like&#34;&gt;What Class Will Be Like&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both of my classes will meet &amp;ldquo;synchronously.&amp;rdquo; This means we have an assigned meeting time, and we&amp;rsquo;ll gather twice a week. Instead of meeting in Morrissey Hall, though, we&amp;rsquo;ll be meeting virtually using a tool called Zoom. Zoom will allow us to get exposed to course content, meet in small groups, and ask questions. It isn&amp;rsquo;t the same, of course, but I am going to do my best to make sure you get as much of the course experience that you would ordinarily receive as I can give you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My decision to teach synchronously was made after reflecting on last spring, taking a class on online teaching, and then teaching synchronously this Fall. My Spring semester students overwhelmingly suggested to me that I teach synchronously, and I take feedback from students seriously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Details about assignments and readings are available in the &lt;a href = &#34;https://slu-soc5650.github.io/syllabus/&#34; target = &#34;_blank&#34;&gt;syllabus&lt;/a&gt;, but I wanted to give you all a quick high-level preview of two &amp;ldquo;novel&amp;rdquo; aspects of the course. First, I&amp;rsquo;ll be utilizing a &amp;ldquo;flipped&amp;rdquo; course design, where the lecture portions of the course will happen in-part via videos that you need to watch before you come to class. This will allow us to dedicate our virtual class time to discussing cartography, practicing skills together, and then practicing skills separately. This will also give me time to meet with students individually each week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, I&amp;rsquo;m using a project based learning approach to the course. While there are set lab exercises that you will all complete, the homework assignments revolve completely around your final project. I normally give students wide latitude for final project topics. This semester, because we will be entirely remote, I am changing that approach. I am going to strongly encourage you to use one of the two pre-made data sets I will make available. If you feel very strongly about doing something different, and feel like you can take on the extra responsibility for learning a bit more independently, I will have a petition process for choosing a different final project topic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given the structure of our class meetings, and the independent nature of the homework assignments, being present in class is critical. I therefore expect that you will come to class. The syllabus contains all the details, but you can boil the attendance policy down to this: attending class is important, and I will be keeping track of who comes so I can identify students who might need some additional support. If you can&amp;rsquo;t attend classes occasionally, no worries. Recordings will be made available via Blackboard. That said, there are interactive parts of class that you need to be present for, so please attend as much as you possibly can. For undergraduate students in SOC 4650, remember that missing one class is like missing an entire week&amp;rsquo;s worth of classes for a &amp;ldquo;normal&amp;rdquo; undergraduate class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-happens-if-i-get-sick&#34;&gt;What Happens If I Get Sick?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you become unwell, or find yourself taking care of your family or friends, please let me know as soon as possible! I will not ask for documentation, since if you&amp;rsquo;re sick but not &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; sick, the last thing most you will want to do is go to a doctor just to get a note. I am proceeding with a spirit of trust in all of you, and ask you reciprocate that with me. If you need to modify assignment due dates, please let me know prior to those deadlines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-office-hours-will-be-like&#34;&gt;What Office Hours Will Be Like&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My office hours are for you! I don&amp;rsquo;t plan to do other things during this period except chat with students. Please feel free to stop by as often as you would like. It&amp;rsquo;s going to be a little intimidating, of course, dropping in to meet someone virtually who you&amp;rsquo;ve never met in person. But please take the step and come to office hours. Getting to know you all is one of the best parts of my job, and office hours is one of the best ways to do that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just like class, office hours will occur over Zoom as well. There will be two periods:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;9am-10am (by appointment only)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;10am-10:45am (open)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the appointment only period, you will be able to sign-up for 15 or 30 minute meetings with me via a service called Calendly. Once you sign-up for a slot, you&amp;rsquo;ll get an invitation that includes Zoom meeting information. For the open, drop-in period, you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to come to a dedicated Zoom meeting that has a &amp;ldquo;waiting room.&amp;rdquo; I&amp;rsquo;ll bring one student in from the waiting room as a time so that we can meet privately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;provisos&#34;&gt;Provisos&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my plan as of January 25th, 2021. I may modify it further as we progress through the the semester. If I become sick or a member of my family becomes ill, modifications will likely be required. I will do my best to keep everyone updated in a timely fashion. Please check your email and Blackboard regularly. I appreciate everyone&amp;rsquo;s willingness to roll with the many punches we are all facing right now. Remember, we are in this together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;acknowledgements&#34;&gt;Acknowledgements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Special thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;https://amycooper.net&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Dr. Amy Cooper&lt;/a&gt; for sharing her language and policies around COVID-19 modifications, which inspired the original version of this page published in Spring 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Around SOC 4650 and SOC 5650</title>
      <link>https://slu-soc5650.github.io/docs/start_around/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://slu-soc5650.github.io/docs/start_around/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-are-the-main-course-resources&#34;&gt;What Are the Main Course Resources?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are five big resources that you&amp;rsquo;ll be using this semester to take this class:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The first is &lt;a href = &#34;https://blackboard.slu.edu/&#34; target = &#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Blackboard&lt;/a&gt;. If you are new to Blackboard, it is a bit clunky, but it gets the job done. We will be using Blackboard primarily because all courses are required to right now. I&amp;rsquo;ll be sharing lecture recordings here along with links to other resources (under &amp;ldquo;Course Materials&amp;rdquo;), posting grades, and using the message board function for answering questions between classes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The second is this course website, which is the central place for finding notes, materials, and links for each course meeting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The third is our &lt;a href = &#34;https://slu-soc5650.github.io&#34; target = &#34;_blank&#34;&gt;syllabus&lt;/a&gt;, which contains all the course policies and due dates.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The fourth is &lt;a href = &#34;https://github.com/slu-soc5650&#34; target = &#34;_blank&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;, which we&amp;rsquo;ll use for sharing lecture materials and submitting assignments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The fifth is our &lt;a href = &#34;http://slu-soc5650.github.io/final-project/&#34; target = &#34;_blank&#34;&gt;final project guide&lt;/a&gt;, which will help walk you through the requirements for the project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do my best to provide links between these difference sources as often as possible. However, I recommend bookmarking the course website, which includes links to everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-is-the-course-organized&#34;&gt;How Is the Course Organized?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The course is organized into four parts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Course Introduction - an introduction to what GIS is, reading maps, and some of the open science tools and concepts we&amp;rsquo;ll be using this semester&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data Cleaning - a pair of meetings focused on preparing and combing &amp;ldquo;tabular&amp;rdquo; data prior to mapping&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Geoprocessing - an overview of modifying and preparing &amp;ldquo;geometric&amp;rdquo; data to customize maps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Map Products with ArcGIS - we&amp;rsquo;ll be focused on ArcGIS Online this semester and specifically will spend time on creating story maps with interactive maps embedded in them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Map Products with R - we&amp;rsquo;ll focus on creating similar interactive maps to what ArcGIS Online offers as well as adding finishing details to the static maps we&amp;rsquo;ve been making all semester&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of the course resources, including the syllabus, Blackboard, and this website, are organized around these modules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-do-i-stay-up-to-date&#34;&gt;How Do I Stay Up-to-date?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First and foremost, come to class. I start every class with &amp;ldquo;front matter&amp;rdquo; that includes announcements and upcoming deadlines. I also end class with &amp;ldquo;back matter,&amp;rdquo; which reviews some of the most important announcements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll also use Blackboard&amp;rsquo;s Announcements page to send you emails about class. This means you &lt;em&gt;need to check your email regularly.&lt;/em&gt; This means every day, multiple times per day.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tips for Using Blackboard</title>
      <link>https://slu-soc5650.github.io/docs/start_blackboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://slu-soc5650.github.io/docs/start_blackboard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-blackboard&#34;&gt;What is Blackboard?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blackboard&lt;/strong&gt; is what we call a &amp;ldquo;learning management system.&amp;rdquo; It provides a platform for online teaching, and we use it for face-to-face courses as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-do-i-use-blackboard&#34;&gt;How Do I Use Blackboard?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go to &lt;a href = &#34;http://blackboard.slu.edu&#34; target = &#34;_blank&#34;&gt;the SLU Blackboard login page&lt;/a&gt;. You may be prompted to use your username, password, and multi-factor authentication credentials when you login. On the landing page, look for &lt;code&gt;SP2021 SOC-4650-01 &amp;amp; SOC-5650-01&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;getting-around-blackboard&#34;&gt;Getting Around Blackboard&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll be taken to the &lt;code&gt;Home Page&lt;/code&gt; page, and can use the left-hand menu to access different course modules. Within those modules will be content folders with links to course materials, assignment submission portals, quizzes, and discussion boards. There is also a resources section, that includes access to &lt;code&gt;My Grades&lt;/code&gt;, where you can get an overview of points you&amp;rsquo;ve earned so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;netiquette-considerations&#34;&gt;Netiquette Considerations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Netiquette is a set of cultural norms (we&amp;rsquo;ll discuss these this semester!) for interacting with classmates online. Different professors might have slightly different ideas about what is appropriate, so don&amp;rsquo;t assume that everything below applies to all classes. These are adapted from &lt;a href=&#34;https://tilt.colostate.edu/TipsAndGuides/Tip/128&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Colorado State&amp;rsquo;s guide to online discussions&lt;/a&gt; and also include some of SLU&amp;rsquo;s best practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No lurking&lt;/strong&gt;: This class requires active participation, you can&amp;rsquo;t just follow discussion board conversations. Please participate!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Report Glitches&lt;/strong&gt;: Blackboard is (kind of crappy) software. Sometimes it doesn&amp;rsquo;t work right. If for any reason you experience difficulty participating, please call, email, or otherwise inform me of the issue. Chances are others are having the same problem.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Help Others&lt;/strong&gt;: You may have more experience with online discussion forums than the person next to you. Give them a hand. Show them it’s not so hard. They’re really going to appreciate it!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be Patient&lt;/strong&gt;: Read everything in the discussion thread before replying. This will help you avoid repeating something someone else has already contributed. Acknowledge the points made with which you agree and suggest alternatives for those with which you don’t.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be Brief&lt;/strong&gt;: You want to be clear—and to articulate your point—without being preachy or pompous. Be direct. Stay on point. Don’t lose yourself, or your readers, in overly wordy sentences or paragraphs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Write Well&lt;/strong&gt;: Feel free to be a bit less formal than you would in a paper (contractions are fine), but make sure your work is easy to read. This means correct spelling, grammatical construction and sentence structure are expected.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cite Your Sources&lt;/strong&gt;: Another big must! If your contribution to the conversation includes the intellectual property (authored material) of others, e.g., books, newspaper, magazine, or journal articles—online or in print—they must be given proper attribution. Use hyperlinks to reference anything online.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Emojis&lt;/strong&gt;: I differ from many of my colleagues here. Use them if you want!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Respect Diversity&lt;/strong&gt;: Respect and be attentive to the diversity of your classmates and instructor.  Before communicating, consider your message in the context of the class’ diversity in race, ethnicity, religion, disabilities, gender, sexual orientation, age, social class, marital status, geography, etc.  Consider the diversity you can see or know – as well as that you cannot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Remember We Can&amp;rsquo;t See You&lt;/strong&gt;: Be cautious when using humor or sarcasm; without the context of facial expressions or other body language, your tone or intent could be missed or misunderstood by others.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Respect Others&#39; Time&lt;/strong&gt;: Respect others’ time and life circumstances, which often don’t allow for an immediate response to a question or comment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No Yelling&lt;/strong&gt;: Step carefully. Beware the electronic footprint you leave behind. Using bold upper-case letters is bad form, like stomping around and yelling at somebody&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No Flaming&lt;/strong&gt;: Criticism must be constructive, well-meaning, and well-articulated. Please, no tantrums. Rants directed at any other contributor are simply unacceptable and will not be tolerated. The same goes for profanity. The academic environment expects higher-order language.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Remember, You Can&amp;rsquo;t Un-Ring the Bell&lt;/strong&gt;: Language is your only tool in an online environment. Be mindful. How others perceive you will be largely—as always—up to you. Once you&amp;rsquo;ve hit the send button, you&amp;rsquo;ve rung the bell.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Review and Revise&lt;/strong&gt;: Review your written posts and responses to ensure that you’ve conveyed exactly what you intended. This is an excellent opportunity to practice your proofreading, revision, and rewriting skills—valuable assets in the professional world for which you are now preparing. I try read my posts out loud. This helps me ensure that grammar and sentence structure are correct, your tone is appropriate, and my post is clear.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tips for Using Zoom</title>
      <link>https://slu-soc5650.github.io/docs/start_zoom/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://slu-soc5650.github.io/docs/start_zoom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-zoom&#34;&gt;What is Zoom?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zoom&lt;/strong&gt; is video conferencing software that we&amp;rsquo;ll be using this semester for class meetings and office hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-do-i-access-zoom&#34;&gt;How Do I Access Zoom?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Links to both will be provided through our course Blackboard site. If you have your own Zoom account that is separate from your SLU account, you &lt;em&gt;must&lt;/em&gt; use your SLU account. Our Zoom meetings require this. Please make sure you sign-out of your personal Zoom account before trying to access course meetings and office hours. I strongly encourage you to access our class meetings via a laptop or desktop computer. You should download the &lt;a href = &#34;https://zoom.us/download&#34; target = &#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Zoom Client for Meetings&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/a&gt; You may be prompted to use your username, password, and multi-factor authentication credentials, so give yourself time before class or an office hours appointment starts. If you need to access Zoom another way, such as calling in, please let me know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-do-i-login-to-zoom&#34;&gt;How Do I Login to Zoom&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to facilitate small-group discussions during class, it is important that you are signed into Zoom via SLU. In-order to ensure that you are signed-in correctly, follow the instructions below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;access-zoom-via-the-web&#34;&gt;Access Zoom via the Web&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to &lt;a href = &#34;http://zoom.us&#34; target = &#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Zoom&amp;rsquo;s website&lt;/a&gt; and make sure you are signed out of any account you have.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to &lt;a href = &#34;https://myslu.slu.edu&#34; target = &#34;_blank&#34;&gt;mySLU&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to &lt;code&gt;Tools&lt;/code&gt; and then click-on &lt;code&gt;Zoom&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;access-zoom-via-an-app&#34;&gt;Access Zoom via an App&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open your app and sign-out of any account you have.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Choose &lt;code&gt;Sign In with SSO&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter &lt;code&gt;slu&lt;/code&gt; for the company domain so that it reads &lt;code&gt;slu.zoom.us&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You will be taken to mySLU and my need to sign-in using your mySLU username and password&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-do-i-use-zoom&#34;&gt;How Do I Use Zoom?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, using Zoom is pretty straightforward once you&amp;rsquo;ve become used it. There are only a few controls you&amp;rsquo;ll need to know how to use. The most important are how to &lt;a href = &#34;https://support.zoom.us/hc/en-us/articles/200941109-Attendee-controls-in-a-meeting&#34; target = &#34;_blank&#34;&gt;turn your audio and video on and off&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ll ask you for &lt;a href = &#34;https://support.zoom.us/hc/en-us/articles/115001286183-Nonverbal-feedback-during-meetings&#34; target = &#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;nonverbal feedback&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; sometimes - these options include raising your hand, saying &amp;ldquo;yes&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;no&amp;rdquo;, and an option to ask me to slow down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is also a &lt;a href = &#34;https://support.zoom.us/hc/en-us/articles/203650445-In-meeting-chat&#34; target = &#34;_blank&#34;&gt;chat feature&lt;/a&gt; we&amp;rsquo;ll be using. When it, though, remember that your course-related communications to the instructor or other students should be considered “professional” (they are not like texts to your friends).  Zoom records chats and I can view them, so please keep that in mind as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-the-best-way-to-arrange-my-zoom-meeting&#34;&gt;What is the Best Way to Arrange my Zoom Meeting?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I strongly recommend that you use Zoom&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href = &#34;https://support.zoom.us/hc/en-us/articles/115004802843-Side-by-side-Mode-for-screen-sharing&#34; target = &#34;_blank&#34;&gt;side-by-side mode&lt;/a&gt; for screen sharing. When you are in side-by-side mode, choosing &amp;ldquo;Speaker View&amp;rdquo; will limit the number of webcams you see to just the person speaking. This arrangement allows you to see both my slides and me at the same time, and can be adjusted with your mouse to make the slides smaller or larger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;do-i-have-to-use-my-microphone&#34;&gt;Do I Have To Use My Microphone?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you come to class, please mute your microphone. If I call on you and you&amp;rsquo;ve raised your hand, please remember to un-mute yourself before speaking!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;do-i-have-to-use-my-camera&#34;&gt;Do I Have To Use My Camera?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During lectures, you are not required to have your camera on - it is entirely up to you. I personally appreciate seeing a few students&#39; faces while I teach, so if you want to leave your camera on, you&amp;rsquo;ll be doing me a favor! But like I said, it isn&amp;rsquo;t required for lectures. However, when we use the &amp;ldquo;breakout room&amp;rdquo; feature for small group discussions, you are expected to have your camera on. These discussions will occur regularly during class meetings, so please keep that in mind as you get ready and prepare your work space before class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-if-i-am-having-technical-issues&#34;&gt;What If I Am Having Technical Issues?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to email me at &lt;a href = &#34;mailto:chris.prener@slu.edu&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:chris.prener@slu.edu&#34;&gt;chris.prener@slu.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. If it is during class, I may not respond right away. That is why we record course meetings, however. If you find that my video or audio is not working well, please let me know in the chat!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;screen-sharing&#34;&gt;Screen Sharing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the key ways we&amp;rsquo;ll work together to solve issues you are confronting is with screen sharing. To be prepared to share your screen, please make sure you have a minimal number of windows open, and be conscious of what those windows contain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;other-considerations&#34;&gt;Other Considerations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following are Saint Louis University&amp;rsquo;s best practices for using Zoom:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mute your microphone when you are not speaking.  Remember to “un-mute” yourself just prior to speaking.  Identify yourself when you begin speaking.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expect a few seconds of delay in getting a response from the instructor or another class member to a question; wait before repeating your question or assuming it was not heard.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If possible, position your camera such that your video feed does not capture too much of your surroundings or other activity/sound from your home/location.  Be conscious of posters, art, or other surroundings that others might find offensive or inappropriate for an educational context.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use the “Raise Hand” and “Chat” (or similar) features of.  This limits verbal interruptions and the confusion generated when multiple people try to speak at once.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Just as in an on-ground, face-to-face class, limit side conversations, multi-tasking (on your computer or otherwise), and use of your cellphone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Temporarily turn off your video feed and mute your microphone when engaged in any non-class conversation or activity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Respect and be attentive to the diversity of your classmates and instructor.  Before communicating, consider your message in the context of the class’ diversity in race, ethnicity, religion, disabilities, gender, sexual orientation, age, social class, marital status, geography, etc.  Consider the diversity you can see or know – as well as that you cannot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remember that video-based class sessions (including chat transcripts) may be recorded and retrieved for later viewing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>License</title>
      <link>https://slu-soc5650.github.io/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://slu-soc5650.github.io/license/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;creative-commons-attribution-40-international-cc-by-40&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International (CC-BY 4.0)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creative Commons Corporation (“Creative Commons”) is not a law firm and does not provide legal services or legal advice. Distribution of Creative Commons public licenses does not create a lawyer-client or other relationship. Creative Commons makes its licenses and related information available on an “as-is” basis. Creative Commons gives no warranties regarding its licenses, any material licensed under their terms and conditions, or any related information. Creative Commons disclaims all liability for damages resulting from their use to the fullest extent possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;using-creative-commons-public-licenses&#34;&gt;Using Creative Commons Public Licenses&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creative Commons public licenses provide a standard set of terms and conditions that creators and other rights holders may use to share original works of authorship and other material subject to copyright and certain other rights specified in the public license below. The following considerations are for informational purposes only, are not exhaustive, and do not form part of our licenses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Considerations for licensors:&lt;/strong&gt; Our public licenses are intended for use by those authorized to give the public permission to use material in ways otherwise restricted by copyright and certain other rights. Our licenses are irrevocable. Licensors should read and understand the terms and conditions of the license they choose before applying it. Licensors should also secure all rights necessary before applying our licenses so that the public can reuse the material as expected. Licensors should clearly mark any material not subject to the license. This includes other CC-licensed material, or material used under an exception or limitation to copyright. &lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.creativecommons.org/Considerations_for_licensors_and_licensees#Considerations_for_licensors&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;More considerations for licensors&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Considerations for the public:&lt;/strong&gt; By using one of our public licenses, a licensor grants the public permission to use the licensed material under specified terms and conditions. If the licensor’s permission is not necessary for any reason–for example, because of any applicable exception or limitation to copyright–then that use is not regulated by the license. Our licenses grant only permissions under copyright and certain other rights that a licensor has authority to grant. Use of the licensed material may still be restricted for other reasons, including because others have copyright or other rights in the material. A licensor may make special requests, such as asking that all changes be marked or described. Although not required by our licenses, you are encouraged to respect those requests where reasonable. &lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.creativecommons.org/Considerations_for_licensors_and_licensees#Considerations_for_licensees&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;More considerations for the public&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;creative-commons-attribution-40-international-public-license&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International Public License&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By exercising the Licensed Rights (defined below), You accept and agree to be bound by the terms and conditions of this Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International Public License (&amp;ldquo;Public License&amp;rdquo;). To the extent this Public License may be interpreted as a contract, You are granted the Licensed Rights in consideration of Your acceptance of these terms and conditions, and the Licensor grants You such rights in consideration of benefits the Licensor receives from making the Licensed Material available under these terms and conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;section-1--definitions&#34;&gt;Section 1 – Definitions.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. &lt;strong&gt;Adapted Material&lt;/strong&gt; means material subject to Copyright and Similar Rights that is derived from or based upon the Licensed Material and in which the Licensed Material is translated, altered, arranged, transformed, or otherwise modified in a manner requiring permission under the Copyright and Similar Rights held by the Licensor. For purposes of this Public License, where the Licensed Material is a musical work, performance, or sound recording, Adapted Material is always produced where the Licensed Material is synched in timed relation with a moving image.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. &lt;strong&gt;Adapter&amp;rsquo;s License&lt;/strong&gt; means the license You apply to Your Copyright and Similar Rights in Your contributions to Adapted Material in accordance with the terms and conditions of this Public License.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c. &lt;strong&gt;Copyright and Similar Rights&lt;/strong&gt; means copyright and/or similar rights closely related to copyright including, without limitation, performance, broadcast, sound recording, and Sui Generis Database Rights, without regard to how the rights are labeled or categorized. For purposes of this Public License, the rights specified in Section 2(b)(1)-(2) are not Copyright and Similar Rights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;d. &lt;strong&gt;Effective Technological Measures&lt;/strong&gt; means those measures that, in the absence of proper authority, may not be circumvented under laws fulfilling obligations under Article 11 of the WIPO Copyright Treaty adopted on December 20, 1996, and/or similar international agreements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;e. &lt;strong&gt;Exceptions and Limitations&lt;/strong&gt; means fair use, fair dealing, and/or any other exception or limitation to Copyright and Similar Rights that applies to Your use of the Licensed Material.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;f. &lt;strong&gt;Licensed Material&lt;/strong&gt; means the artistic or literary work, database, or other material to which the Licensor applied this Public License.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;g. &lt;strong&gt;Licensed Rights&lt;/strong&gt; means the rights granted to You subject to the terms and conditions of this Public License, which are limited to all Copyright and Similar Rights that apply to Your use of the Licensed Material and that the Licensor has authority to license.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;h. &lt;strong&gt;Licensor&lt;/strong&gt; means the individual(s) or entity(ies) granting rights under this Public License.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i. &lt;strong&gt;Share&lt;/strong&gt; means to provide material to the public by any means or process that requires permission under the Licensed Rights, such as reproduction, public display, public performance, distribution, dissemination, communication, or importation, and to make material available to the public including in ways that members of the public may access the material from a place and at a time individually chosen by them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;j. &lt;strong&gt;Sui Generis Database Rights&lt;/strong&gt; means rights other than copyright resulting from Directive 96/9/EC of the European Parliament and of the Council of 11 March 1996 on the legal protection of databases, as amended and/or succeeded, as well as other essentially equivalent rights anywhere in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;k. &lt;strong&gt;You&lt;/strong&gt; means the individual or entity exercising the Licensed Rights under this Public License. Your has a corresponding meaning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;section-2--scope&#34;&gt;Section 2 – Scope.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;License grant.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Subject to the terms and conditions of this Public License, the Licensor hereby grants You a worldwide, royalty-free, non-sublicensable, non-exclusive, irrevocable license to exercise the Licensed Rights in the Licensed Material to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A. reproduce and Share the Licensed Material, in whole or in part; and&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;B. produce, reproduce, and Share Adapted Material.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exceptions and Limitations.&lt;/strong&gt; For the avoidance of doubt, where Exceptions and Limitations apply to Your use, this Public License does not apply, and You do not need to comply with its terms and conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Term.&lt;/strong&gt; The term of this Public License is specified in Section 6(a).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Media and formats; technical modifications allowed.&lt;/strong&gt; The Licensor authorizes You to exercise the Licensed Rights in all media and formats whether now known or hereafter created, and to make technical modifications necessary to do so. The Licensor waives and/or agrees not to assert any right or authority to forbid You from making technical modifications necessary to exercise the Licensed Rights, including technical modifications necessary to circumvent Effective Technological Measures. For purposes of this Public License, simply making modifications authorized by this Section 2(a)(4) never produces Adapted Material.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Downstream recipients.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A. &lt;strong&gt;Offer from the Licensor – Licensed Material.&lt;/strong&gt; Every recipient of the Licensed Material automatically receives an offer from the Licensor to exercise the Licensed Rights under the terms and conditions of this Public License.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;B. &lt;strong&gt;No downstream restrictions.&lt;/strong&gt; You may not offer or impose any additional or different terms or conditions on, or apply any Effective Technological Measures to, the Licensed Material if doing so restricts exercise of the Licensed Rights by any recipient of the Licensed Material.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No endorsement.&lt;/strong&gt; Nothing in this Public License constitutes or may be construed as permission to assert or imply that You are, or that Your use of the Licensed Material is, connected with, or sponsored, endorsed, or granted official status by, the Licensor or others designated to receive attribution as provided in Section 3(a)(1)(A)(i).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Other rights.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moral rights, such as the right of integrity, are not licensed under this Public License, nor are publicity, privacy, and/or other similar personality rights; however, to the extent possible, the Licensor waives and/or agrees not to assert any such rights held by the Licensor to the limited extent necessary to allow You to exercise the Licensed Rights, but not otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Patent and trademark rights are not licensed under this Public License.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To the extent possible, the Licensor waives any right to collect royalties from You for the exercise of the Licensed Rights, whether directly or through a collecting society under any voluntary or waivable statutory or compulsory licensing scheme. In all other cases the Licensor expressly reserves any right to collect such royalties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;section-3--license-conditions&#34;&gt;Section 3 – License Conditions.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your exercise of the Licensed Rights is expressly made subject to the following conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Attribution.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If You Share the Licensed Material (including in modified form), You must:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A. retain the following if it is supplied by the Licensor with the Licensed Material:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i. identification of the creator(s) of the Licensed Material and any others designated to receive attribution, in any reasonable manner requested by the Licensor (including by pseudonym if designated);&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ii. a copyright notice;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;iii. a notice that refers to this Public License;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;iv. a notice that refers to the disclaimer of warranties;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;v. a URI or hyperlink to the Licensed Material to the extent reasonably practicable;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;B. indicate if You modified the Licensed Material and retain an indication of any previous modifications; and&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C. indicate the Licensed Material is licensed under this Public License, and include the text of, or the URI or hyperlink to, this Public License.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may satisfy the conditions in Section 3(a)(1) in any reasonable manner based on the medium, means, and context in which You Share the Licensed Material. For example, it may be reasonable to satisfy the conditions by providing a URI or hyperlink to a resource that includes the required information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If requested by the Licensor, You must remove any of the information required by Section 3(a)(1)(A) to the extent reasonably practicable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If You Share Adapted Material You produce, the Adapter&amp;rsquo;s License You apply must not prevent recipients of the Adapted Material from complying with this Public License.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;section-4--sui-generis-database-rights&#34;&gt;Section 4 – Sui Generis Database Rights.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where the Licensed Rights include Sui Generis Database Rights that apply to Your use of the Licensed Material:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. for the avoidance of doubt, Section 2(a)(1) grants You the right to extract, reuse, reproduce, and Share all or a substantial portion of the contents of the database;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. if You include all or a substantial portion of the database contents in a database in which You have Sui Generis Database Rights, then the database in which You have Sui Generis Database Rights (but not its individual contents) is Adapted Material; and&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c. You must comply with the conditions in Section 3(a) if You Share all or a substantial portion of the contents of the database.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the avoidance of doubt, this Section 4 supplements and does not replace Your obligations under this Public License where the Licensed Rights include other Copyright and Similar Rights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;section-5--disclaimer-of-warranties-and-limitation-of-liability&#34;&gt;Section 5 – Disclaimer of Warranties and Limitation of Liability.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. &lt;strong&gt;Unless otherwise separately undertaken by the Licensor, to the extent possible, the Licensor offers the Licensed Material as-is and as-available, and makes no representations or warranties of any kind concerning the Licensed Material, whether express, implied, statutory, or other. This includes, without limitation, warranties of title, merchantability, fitness for a particular purpose, non-infringement, absence of latent or other defects, accuracy, or the presence or absence of errors, whether or not known or discoverable. Where disclaimers of warranties are not allowed in full or in part, this disclaimer may not apply to You.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. &lt;strong&gt;To the extent possible, in no event will the Licensor be liable to You on any legal theory (including, without limitation, negligence) or otherwise for any direct, special, indirect, incidental, consequential, punitive, exemplary, or other losses, costs, expenses, or damages arising out of this Public License or use of the Licensed Material, even if the Licensor has been advised of the possibility of such losses, costs, expenses, or damages. Where a limitation of liability is not allowed in full or in part, this limitation may not apply to You.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c. The disclaimer of warranties and limitation of liability provided above shall be interpreted in a manner that, to the extent possible, most closely approximates an absolute disclaimer and waiver of all liability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;section-6--term-and-termination&#34;&gt;Section 6 – Term and Termination.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. This Public License applies for the term of the Copyright and Similar Rights licensed here. However, if You fail to comply with this Public License, then Your rights under this Public License terminate automatically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. Where Your right to use the Licensed Material has terminated under Section 6(a), it reinstates:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;automatically as of the date the violation is cured, provided it is cured within 30 days of Your discovery of the violation; or&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;upon express reinstatement by the Licensor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the avoidance of doubt, this Section 6(b) does not affect any right the Licensor may have to seek remedies for Your violations of this Public License.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c. For the avoidance of doubt, the Licensor may also offer the Licensed Material under separate terms or conditions or stop distributing the Licensed Material at any time; however, doing so will not terminate this Public License.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;d. Sections 1, 5, 6, 7, and 8 survive termination of this Public License.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;section-7--other-terms-and-conditions&#34;&gt;Section 7 – Other Terms and Conditions.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. The Licensor shall not be bound by any additional or different terms or conditions communicated by You unless expressly agreed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. Any arrangements, understandings, or agreements regarding the Licensed Material not stated herein are separate from and independent of the terms and conditions of this Public License.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;section-8--interpretation&#34;&gt;Section 8 – Interpretation.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. For the avoidance of doubt, this Public License does not, and shall not be interpreted to, reduce, limit, restrict, or impose conditions on any use of the Licensed Material that could lawfully be made without permission under this Public License.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. To the extent possible, if any provision of this Public License is deemed unenforceable, it shall be automatically reformed to the minimum extent necessary to make it enforceable. If the provision cannot be reformed, it shall be severed from this Public License without affecting the enforceability of the remaining terms and conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c. No term or condition of this Public License will be waived and no failure to comply consented to unless expressly agreed to by the Licensor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;d. Nothing in this Public License constitutes or may be interpreted as a limitation upon, or waiver of, any privileges and immunities that apply to the Licensor or You, including from the legal processes of any jurisdiction or authority.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creative Commons is not a party to its public licenses. Notwithstanding, Creative Commons may elect to apply one of its public licenses to material it publishes and in those instances will be considered the “Licensor.” Except for the limited purpose of indicating that material is shared under a Creative Commons public license or as otherwise permitted by the Creative Commons policies published at &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/policies&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;creativecommons.org/policies&lt;/a&gt;, Creative Commons does not authorize the use of the trademark “Creative Commons” or any other trademark or logo of Creative Commons without its prior written consent including, without limitation, in connection with any unauthorized modifications to any of its public licenses or any other arrangements, understandings, or agreements concerning use of licensed material. For the avoidance of doubt, this paragraph does not form part of the public licenses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creative Commons may be contacted at creativecommons.org&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy Policy</title>
      <link>https://slu-soc5650.github.io/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://slu-soc5650.github.io/privacy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Privacy Policy
Your privacy is important to us. It is Christopher Prener&amp;rsquo;s policy to respect your privacy regarding any information we may collect from you across our website, &lt;a href=&#34;http://slu-soc1120.github.io&#34;&gt;http://slu-soc1120.github.io&lt;/a&gt;, and other sites we own and operate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We only ask for personal information when we truly need it to provide a service to you. We collect it by fair and lawful means, with your knowledge and consent. We also let you know why we’re collecting it and how it will be used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We only retain collected information for as long as necessary to provide you with your requested service. What data we store, we’ll protect within commercially acceptable means to prevent loss and theft, as well as unauthorised access, disclosure, copying, use or modification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We don’t share any personally identifying information publicly or with third-parties, except when required to by law.
Our website may link to external sites that are not operated by us. Please be aware that we have no control over the content and practices of these sites, and cannot accept responsibility or liability for their respective privacy policies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are free to refuse our request for your personal information, with the understanding that we may be unable to provide you with some of your desired services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your continued use of our website will be regarded as acceptance of our practices around privacy and personal information. If you have any questions about how we handle user data and personal information, feel free to contact us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This policy is effective as of 10 August 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generated by GetTerms.io&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terms</title>
      <link>https://slu-soc5650.github.io/terms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://slu-soc5650.github.io/terms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Terms&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By accessing the website at &lt;a href=&#34;http://slu-soc1120.github.io&#34;&gt;http://slu-soc1120.github.io&lt;/a&gt;, you are agreeing to be bound by these terms of service, all applicable laws and regulations, and agree that you are responsible for compliance with any applicable local laws. If you do not agree with any of these terms, you are prohibited from using or accessing this site. The materials contained in this website are protected by applicable copyright and trademark law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Use License&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Creative Commons License&#34; style=&#34;border-width:0&#34; src=&#34;https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by/4.0/88x31.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a &lt;a href=&#34;https://slu-soc5650.github.io/license&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International (CC-BY 4.0) License&lt;/a&gt;. You are free to &lt;strong&gt;share&lt;/strong&gt; (copy and redistribute the material in any medium or format) and &lt;strong&gt;adapt&lt;/strong&gt; (remix, transform, and build upon the material for any purpose, even commercially). The licensor cannot revoke these freedoms as long as you follow the license terms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, you must provide &lt;strong&gt;attribution&lt;/strong&gt; (you must give appropriate credit, provide a link to the license, and indicate if changes were made). You may not apply legal terms or technological measures that legally restrict others from doing anything the license permits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You do not have to comply with the license for elements of the material in the public domain or where your use is permitted by an applicable exception or limitation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No warranties are given. The license may not give you all of the permissions necessary for your intended use. For example, other rights such as publicity, privacy, or moral rights may limit how you use the material.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This license applies only to the &lt;strong&gt;content&lt;/strong&gt; of the site and does not apply to Hugo (released under an &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/about/license/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Apache 2.0 License&lt;/a&gt;) or the Academic Theme (released under an &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/blob/master/LICENSE.md&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;MIT License&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Disclaimer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The materials on Christopher Prener&amp;rsquo;s website are provided on an &amp;lsquo;as is&amp;rsquo; basis. Christopher Prener makes no warranties, expressed or implied, and hereby disclaims and negates all other warranties including, without limitation, implied warranties or conditions of merchantability, fitness for a particular purpose, or non-infringement of intellectual property or other violation of rights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further, Christopher Prener does not warrant or make any representations concerning the accuracy, likely results, or reliability of the use of the materials on its website or otherwise relating to such materials or on any sites linked to this site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Limitations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In no event shall Christopher Prener or its suppliers be liable for any damages (including, without limitation, damages for loss of data or profit, or due to business interruption) arising out of the use or inability to use the materials on Christopher Prener&amp;rsquo;s website, even if Christopher Prener or a Christopher Prener authorized representative has been notified orally or in writing of the possibility of such damage. Because some jurisdictions do not allow limitations on implied warranties, or limitations of liability for consequential or incidental damages, these limitations may not apply to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Accuracy of materials&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The materials appearing on Christopher Prener&amp;rsquo;s website could include technical, typographical, or photographic errors. Christopher Prener does not warrant that any of the materials on its website are accurate, complete or current. Christopher Prener may make changes to the materials contained on its website at any time without notice. However Christopher Prener does not make any commitment to update the materials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Links&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Christopher Prener has not reviewed all of the sites linked to its website and is not responsible for the contents of any such linked site. The inclusion of any link does not imply endorsement by Christopher Prener of the site. Use of any such linked website is at the user&amp;rsquo;s own risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Modifications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Christopher Prener may revise these terms of service for its website at any time without notice. By using this website you are agreeing to be bound by the then current version of these terms of service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8. Governing Law&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These terms and conditions are governed by and construed in accordance with the laws of Missouri and you irrevocably submit to the exclusive jurisdiction of the courts in that State or location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generated by GetTerms.io&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Approaching Coursework</title>
      <link>https://slu-soc5650.github.io/docs/start_coursework/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://slu-soc5650.github.io/docs/start_coursework/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students have varying experiences learning computational techniques. For some, the math and programming that are the foundation for modern data science techniques come naturally. For others, being introduced to these concepts can be an anxiety producing experience. I am fond the phrase &amp;ldquo;your mileage will vary&amp;rdquo; for describing these differences - no two students have the exact same experience taking a computational methods course. While some of this is specific to this course, the general outlook on approaching data science work that I describe below is hopefully applicable in a far wider arena.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;zen-and-the-art-of-data-analysis&#34;&gt;Zen and the Art of Data Analysis&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest challenges with this course can be controlling the anxiety that comes along with learning new skills. &lt;code&gt;R&lt;/code&gt; syntax, GIS terms, and Markdown can seem like foreign alphabets at first. Debugging &lt;code&gt;R&lt;/code&gt; syntax can be both challenging and a large time suck, in part because you are not yet fluent with this language. Imagine trying to proofread a document written in a language that you only know in a cursory way but where you must find minute inconsistencies like misplaced commas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this reason, I also think it is worth reminding you that many students in the social sciences struggle with computational methods at first. It is normal to find this challenging and frustrating. I find that students who can recognize when they are beginning to go around in circles are often the most successful at managing the issues that will certainly arise during this course. Recognizing the signs that you are starting to spin your wheels and taking either ten minutes, an hour or two, or a day away from computational coursework is often a much better approach than trying to power through problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data analysis therefore requires a certain mindfulness or what I call &amp;ldquo;habits of mind and habits of method.&amp;rdquo; These mental habits extend past being able to recognize that frustration is setting in. They also include the mental habits needed for &lt;a href=&#34;#getting-and-staying-organized&#34;&gt;Getting and Staying Organized&lt;/a&gt; and strategies for &lt;a href=&#34;https://slu-soc5650.github.io/docs/getting-help/&#34;&gt;Getting Help&lt;/a&gt; as you navigate the inevitable errors that come with learning new analytically skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;getting-and-staying-organized&#34;&gt;Getting and Staying Organized&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doing data science work, and having the space to step away for a day as the last section suggests, requires discipline and organization. Similarly, computational coursework can demanding not just because it is complex but because the courses often have a number of moving pieces that you need to keep track of. Being mindful of this challenge from the beginning, and taking steps to plan for it, is an important part of this course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;keeping-track-of-where-you-are&#34;&gt;Keeping Track of Where You Are&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students who have some system for tracking their work and creating to-do lists are often the most successful in this course, not because they have a fundamentally better grasp on the content but because they simply are more organized. If you have never thought particularly hard about how you manage tasks, now is an excellent time to start doing so. You do not need fancy computer software to accomplish this, though there are an array of possibilities if you do want to use software to keep yourself organized. A legal pad or a notebook can be just as effective as a $50 to-do list manager. The point is, do &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am fond of recommending the &lt;a href=&#34;http://gettingthingsdone.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Getting Things Done&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; methodology to students as part of thinking more holistically about staying organized. The website &lt;a href=&#34;https://lifehacker.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Lifehacker&lt;/a&gt; posted an &lt;a href=&#34;https://lifehacker.com/productivity-101-a-primer-to-the-getting-things-done-1551880955&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;excellent introduction to GTD&lt;/a&gt; that is a great way to get a sense of how it works and find additional resources for implementing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The GTD website has a &lt;a href=&#34;http://gettingthingsdone.com/common-tools-software/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;great list of software&lt;/a&gt; for those of you looking for a to-do list application. One that isn&amp;rsquo;t listed that I have used for collaborating with my student research team is &lt;a href=&#34;https://trello.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Trello&lt;/a&gt;, a freemium website that allows you to create simple to-do lists. It isn&amp;rsquo;t sophisticated enough for implementing GTD, but it is more than sufficient for managing to-do lists related to this course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;virtual-office-hours&#34;&gt;Virtual Office Hours&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We don&amp;rsquo;t always do a great job of explaining office hours to students, so I&amp;rsquo;ve put together &lt;a href=&#34;https://chris-prener.github.io/resources/students/office-hours/&#34; target = &#34;_blank&#34;&gt;an explainer on my website&lt;/a&gt; to lay out what office hours are for, when you should come, and remind you that it is OK to stop by without an agenda!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the 2020-2021 academic year, there are two types of office hours that I have:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Appointments: Appoints are available for an hour each week from 9am CST to 10am CST on Wednesdays. You can sign-up for an appointment by visiting my &lt;a href = &#34;https://calendly.com/chris-prener&#34; target = &#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Calendly page&lt;/a&gt;. Select either a 15 minute or 30 minute meeting, and fill out your details. Once you submit the meeting request, you&amp;rsquo;ll receive a calendar invitation and a Zoom link.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drop-in: From 10am CST to 10:45am CST on Wednesdays, I&amp;rsquo;ll be available via Zoom for drop-in office hours. No appointment is required, and you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to come to a dedicated Zoom meeting that has a &amp;ldquo;waiting room.&amp;rdquo; I&amp;rsquo;ll bring one student in from the waiting room as a time so that we can meet privately. The link for this is available on Blackboard.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If these times do not work for your class schedule, please email me to set-up a meeting at another time! I&amp;rsquo;ll work with you to find a time that works for both of our schedules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;other-tips&#34;&gt;Other Tips&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to my &lt;a href=&#34;https://chris-prener.github.io/resources/students/office-hours/&#34; target = &#34;_blank&#34;&gt;office hours explainer&lt;/a&gt;, I have the following articles on my website:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://chris-prener.github.io/resources/students/little-things/&#34; target = &#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Doing the Little Things Right&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; - tips for surviving in this brave new world you&amp;rsquo;ve found yourself in at a university&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://chris-prener.github.io/resources/students/writing/&#34; target = &#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Tips for Writing in the Social Sciences&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; - tips for writing in social science classes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preparing Your Computer</title>
      <link>https://slu-soc5650.github.io/docs/start_prep/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://slu-soc5650.github.io/docs/start_prep/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before you begin the semester, there are a number of things that you should do to help set yourself up for success. &lt;strong&gt;All of the applicable sections below should be completed before our first class on February 1st.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;computer-prep&#34;&gt;Computer Prep&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please work through the following steps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make sure your operating system is up-to-date. If you are able, I would also recommend upgrading your computer to the most recent release of its operating system that the computer can run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On macOS, you can do this through the &lt;a href=&#34;https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT201541&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;App Store&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;The one exception is upgrading to Big Sur. I have not yet done so and, if you have not either, I recommend holding off. I will not be testing out our course materials with Big Sur this semester.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Both &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dummies.com/computers/computer-networking/network-security/how-to-manually-check-for-windows-7-updates/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Windows 7&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/help/4027667/windows-update-windows-10&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Windows 10&lt;/a&gt; have system update tools, though if you have Windows 7, you should consider upgrading to Windows 10.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ll be sharing computer files throughout the semester, so you should ensure that you have functioning anti-virus software and that it is up-to-date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll also need to download files, so you&amp;rsquo;ll need to make sure you have at least &lt;strong&gt;twenty gigabytes&lt;/strong&gt; free if you are not. If you&amp;rsquo;re not sure how to check this, here are some instructions for &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lifewire.com/how-to-check-free-hard-drive-space-in-windows-2619187&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Windows&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.macworld.com/article/2972775/os-x/how-to-check-your-macs-free-hard-drive-space.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;macOS&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Options for de-cluttering include deleting files that are no longer needed, moving files to an external device, moving files to a cloud storage system, or upgrading the internal hard drive (may not be possible for macOS users and some Windows users).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make sure you know how to access your computer&amp;rsquo;s file management system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On macOS, this means being comfortable with Finder.app for finding folders, making new ones, and opening files. Here are some tips for using Finder on recent versions of &lt;a href=&#34;https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT201732&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;macOS&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On Windows, this means being comfortable with Windows File Explorer for finding folders, making new ones, and opening files. Here are some tips for using File Explorer on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dummies.com/computers/operating-systems/windows-7/how-to-navigate-windows-7-with-windows-explorer/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Windows 7&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dummies.com/computers/operating-systems/windows-10/how-does-file-explorer-work-in-windows-10/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Windows 10&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;r&#34;&gt;R&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;base-r&#34;&gt;Base R&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can download &lt;code&gt;R&lt;/code&gt; from its &lt;a href=&#34;https://cloud.r-project.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;. Choose &amp;ldquo;Download R for (Mac) OS X&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Download R for Windows&amp;rdquo;. Windows users should look for text that says &amp;ldquo;install R for the first time&amp;rdquo; and click the &lt;code&gt;base&lt;/code&gt; to the left of that text. Both macOS and Windows users should install &lt;code&gt;R&lt;/code&gt; version 4.0.3, known as &amp;ldquo;Bunny-Wunnies Freak Out&amp;rdquo; (&lt;code&gt;R&lt;/code&gt; version nicknames come from &lt;a href=&#34;https://livefreeordichotomize.com/2017/09/28/r-release-names/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Peanuts&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you already have &lt;code&gt;R&lt;/code&gt; installed, please make sure you have the latest version. You can upgrade it using the same process for a new installation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;rstudio&#34;&gt;RStudio&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RStudio is a graphical user interface for &lt;code&gt;R&lt;/code&gt; that will make learning the language and using it much, much easier. You should download the &lt;em&gt;free&lt;/em&gt; version of RStudio from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rstudio.com/products/rstudio/download/#download&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;their website&lt;/a&gt;. Choose the appropriate installer for your platform. Make sure &lt;code&gt;R&lt;/code&gt; is already installed before installing RStudio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you already have RStudio installed, please make sure you have the latest version. You can upgrade it using the same process for a new installation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;r-packages&#34;&gt;R Packages&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The packages we will need this semester can be downloaded using the following code chunk in RStudio&amp;rsquo;s console:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-r&#34;&gt;install.packages(c(&amp;quot;tidyverse&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;here&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;janitor&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;knitr&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;leaflet&amp;quot;,
  &amp;quot;mapview&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;measurements&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;naniar&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;RColorBrewer&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;remotes&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;rmarkdown&amp;quot;,
  &amp;quot;sf&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;testDriveR&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;tidycensus&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;tigris&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;tmap&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;viridis&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;webshot&amp;quot;))
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should only have to run this once per computer. If you are not sure where to find the console, don&amp;rsquo;t worry - we&amp;rsquo;ll talk about this on the first day of class!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;phantomjs&#34;&gt;PhantomJS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PhantomJS is a means for creating &amp;ldquo;headless&amp;rdquo; web-browsers and thus rendering the output of HTML widegts in &lt;code&gt;knitr&lt;/code&gt; documents. It makes it possible to get a screengrab of a &lt;code&gt;leaflet&lt;/code&gt; map when you &amp;ldquo;knit&amp;rdquo; your &lt;code&gt;.Rmd&lt;/code&gt; files, for instance. To install it, use the following code chunk in RStudio&amp;rsquo;s console:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-r&#34;&gt;webshot::install_phantomjs()
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like installing packages, you should only have to run this once per computer. Again, if you&amp;rsquo;re not sure about using the console, don&amp;rsquo;t worry - we&amp;rsquo;ll talk about this on the first day of class!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;get-started-with-github&#34;&gt;Get Started with GitHub&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The service that is hosting this website is called &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;. GitHub is used by programmers, data scientists, and researchers for hosting computer code, data, and project materials (like websites). We will be using GitHub extensively this semester. You will need a free account, which you can sign up for one from GitHub&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;homepage&lt;/a&gt;. If you already have a GitHub account, you do not need a new one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you have a GitHub user name, send Chris an email with it so that you can be added to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/slu-soc5650&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;SOC 4650 &amp;amp; SOC 5650 organization&lt;/a&gt;. After you have been added to the organization, you should find your assignments repository and check the &lt;strong&gt;Issues&lt;/strong&gt; tab. There should be an open &lt;strong&gt;Issue&lt;/strong&gt; describing how feedback will be disseminated this semester. Please read it and then &lt;em&gt;close the issue&lt;/em&gt; so that we know you&amp;rsquo;ve seen it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;github-desktop&#34;&gt;GitHub Desktop&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the applications above, everyone will need a local installation of GitHub Desktop, which is a graphical user interface for accessing Git and GitHub.com. It can be downloaded for free from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://desktop.github.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;application&amp;rsquo;s website&lt;/a&gt;. You will need to download and run the installer. Once it is complete, you will need to login to the application with your &lt;a href=&#34;https://slu-soc5650.github.io/docs/onboarding&#34;&gt;GitHub.com username and password&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting 01 - Course Introduction</title>
      <link>https://slu-soc5650.github.io/docs/meeting_01/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://slu-soc5650.github.io/docs/meeting_01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;br&gt; 
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-info&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Please make sure you have gone through the Course Onboarding section of Blackboard and all of the Getting Started pages of the Course Docs! In addition, there are two videos to watch below and a short reading to complete before you submit the first entry ticket.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;meeting-goals&#34;&gt;Meeting Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This course meeting has an emphasis on the following goals:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduce the basic themes of the course&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Critique an example web map and the process used to create it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Construct simple interactive web maps using leaflet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;before-class&#34;&gt;Before Class&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;tasks&#34;&gt;Tasks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Complete all course onboarding tasks posted in Module 1 if you have not already done so (see Blackboard)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Complete the two videos and the reading listed on the syllabus (see below)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Submit Entry Ticket 1 (see Blackboard)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;open-data-and-gis-in-los-angeles&#34;&gt;Open Data and GIS in Los Angeles&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the course learning outcomes is titled &amp;ldquo;GISc and Public Policy&amp;rdquo;. Much of the data that we will use this semester is available to us because governmental agencies at the Federal, state, and local levels have published it and made it accessible. We call the movement to make as much data available as possible &amp;ldquo;open data&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Different governments have embraced the open data movement to varying degrees, and the video below discusses Los Angeles&#39; integration of open data and GIS. It is a 9 minute talk given by L.A.&amp;rsquo;s former Chief Data Officer &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/lcoral&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Lilian P. Coral&lt;/a&gt;. The talk was part of a conference organized by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.esri.com/en-us/home&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ESRI&lt;/a&gt;, the makers of ArcGIS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/etdwa768Zms&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you&amp;rsquo;ve watched the video, check out the web application featured in the video that &lt;a href=&#34;http://ladot.maps.arcgis.com/apps/MapJournal/index.html?appid=a45d3efd7b1d4ef49f362caadb4754b0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;visualizes pedestrian and cyclist injuries in Los Angeles&lt;/a&gt;. You can also visit L.A.&amp;rsquo;s open data website called &lt;a href=&#34;http://geohub.lacity.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GeoHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;analysis-development&#34;&gt;Analysis Development&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making a produce like L.A.&amp;rsquo;s visualization of pedestrian and cyclist injuries is a complicated effort. Data must be obtained from various sources, modified (a process we call &amp;ldquo;data wrangling&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;data cleaning&amp;rdquo;), and then linked with map coordinates. Once it is ready to be mapped, the web application must be designed and created. We&amp;rsquo;ll call this large-scale process a &amp;ldquo;workflow&amp;rdquo; this semester.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The workflow that we&amp;rsquo;ll use is opinionated - there is a strong premise that underlies the workflow about the ways in which spatial data (and data more generally) should be obtained, stored, modified, and mapped. Hilary Parker is a data scientist at &lt;a href=&#34;http://stitchfix.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Stichfix&lt;/a&gt; and also runs a data science podcast called &lt;a href=&#34;http://nssdeviations.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Not So Standard Deviations&lt;/a&gt;. She has been speaking recently about an idea called opinionated analysis development. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rstudio.com/resources/videos/opinionated-analysis-development/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt; linked to below is a 25 minute talk she gave on this idea last year, and she now has a &lt;a href=&#34;https://peerj.com/preprints/3210/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;draft paper&lt;/a&gt; out on the topic as well. Our workflow for this semester is closely linked to the ideas she discusses in this talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many (but not all of you) will have experienced some parts of these processes before. Perhaps you&amp;rsquo;ve used Microsoft Excel to organize some information or used SPSS to analyze some quantitative data. We won&amp;rsquo;t be using those tools. Instead, this course will emphasize the use of other tools that support reproducible, accurate, and collaborative data analysis. Throughout the semester, we&amp;rsquo;ll discuss why these tools are important and the advantages they have over other products that are out there. Inspired by Hilary&amp;rsquo;s idea of opinionated analysis development, our goal each week will be to focus on the &lt;em&gt;processes&lt;/em&gt; that can be used to increase the reproducibility and accuracy of our geospatial work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of these processes, like using RMarkdown, are introduced in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://plain-text.co&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;introductory &amp;ldquo;chapter&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; (it is quite short!) to Duke University sociologist &lt;a href=&#34;http://kieranhealy.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Kieran Healy&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; primer &lt;a href=&#34;http://plain-text.co&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Plain Person&amp;rsquo;s Guide to Plain Text Social Science&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. This is the one &lt;em&gt;required&lt;/em&gt; reading for the entry ticket (though there are several optional ones listed on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://slu-soc5650.github.io/syllabus/course-preview.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;syllabus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://rstudio.com/resources/rstudioconf-2017/opinionated-analysis-development/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://slu-soc5650.github.io/media/opinionatedAnalysis.png&#34; alt=&#34;opinionatedAnalysis&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many (but not all of you) will have experienced some parts of these processes before. Perhaps you&amp;rsquo;ve used Microsoft Excel to organize some information or used SPSS to analyze some quantitative data. We won&amp;rsquo;t be using those tools. Instead, this course will emphasize the use of other tools that support reproducible, accurate, and collaborative data analysis. Throughout the semester, we&amp;rsquo;ll discuss why these tools are important and the advantages they have over other products that are out there. Inspired by Hilary&amp;rsquo;s idea of opinionated analysis development, our goal each week will be to focus on the &lt;em&gt;processes&lt;/em&gt; that can be used to increase the reproducibility and accuracy of our geospatial work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of these processes, like using RMarkdown, are introduced in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://plain-text.co&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;introductory &amp;ldquo;chapter&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; (it is quite short!) to Duke University sociologist &lt;a href=&#34;http://kieranhealy.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Kieran Healy&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; primer &lt;a href=&#34;http://plain-text.co&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Plain Person&amp;rsquo;s Guide to Plain Text Social Science&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. This is the one &lt;em&gt;required&lt;/em&gt; reading for the entry ticket (though there are several optional ones listed on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://slu-soc5650.github.io/syllabus/module-1-course-introduction.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;syllabus&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;lecture-01-entry-ticket&#34;&gt;Lecture-01 Entry Ticket&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The entry ticket for the first lecture asks three follow-up questions about these videos and L.A.&amp;rsquo;s interactive website. Please answer these questions and submit them before class on &lt;strong&gt;February 1st&lt;/strong&gt;. Answers &lt;strong&gt;must&lt;/strong&gt; be submitted through &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfI66TDRFH6xsj7getQZ3UXo8d7JeiMaCNH0WOhJZcXcevx7g/viewform?usp=sf_link&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Google Forms&lt;/a&gt; and each response should be three to four sentences in length. The questions are provided here for reference:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Briefly describe how the City of Los Angeles uses data and mapping to inform how they deliver city services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After viewing the interactive map showing pedestrian and cyclist injuries, describe what you thought of the map. Some example considerations could include: was it easy to read? to navigate? did you like the colors? was it missing relevant data?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In your own words, what are the key aspects of opinionated analysis development?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are some of the advantages of using plain text for data analysis?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The entry ticket also asks for an update on your course onboarding process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;during-class&#34;&gt;During Class&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;slides&#34;&gt;Slides&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;script async class=&#34;speakerdeck-embed&#34; data-id=&#34;3b023eb9d7ee463faea3a90532221987&#34; data-ratio=&#34;1.33333333333333&#34; src=&#34;//speakerdeck.com/assets/embed.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;after-class&#34;&gt;After Class&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;tasks-1&#34;&gt;Tasks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Complete Lab-01 after and come to Meeting 02 prepared to submit it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;lab-01&#34;&gt;Lab-01&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please finish Lab-01, which is located in the &lt;code&gt;module-1-intro&lt;/code&gt; folder you already download in &lt;code&gt;assignments/lab-01/docs/lab-01.Rmd&lt;/code&gt;. Once you&amp;rsquo;ve opened that (use the &lt;code&gt;lab-01.Rproj&lt;/code&gt; R project file in &lt;code&gt;assignments/lab-01&lt;/code&gt;), you&amp;rsquo;ll need to round-out the narrative text, add code to open the grocery store data (located in &lt;code&gt;assignments/lab-01/data&lt;/code&gt;), and make an interactive map of grocery stores in St. Louis City and County using &lt;code&gt;leaflet&lt;/code&gt;. All of this can be accomplished using the code we used in class today. A replication file is already present in the &lt;code&gt;assignments&lt;/code&gt; folder as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;sample-maps&#34;&gt;Sample Maps&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In class, I mentioned that I thought some of my favorite maps are the National Park Service&amp;rsquo;s visitor guides for each of there &amp;ldquo;resources&amp;rdquo; (NPS lingo for different parks, monuments, and sites) and &lt;a href=&#34;https://jamesniehues.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;James Niehues&#39;&lt;/a&gt; legendary ski area maps. The NPS brochures themselves aren&amp;rsquo;t available online, but some of the maps are! Here are some samples:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;James Niehues&#39; &lt;a href=&#34;https://bigskyresort.com/documents/Big%20Sky/The%20Resort/Trail%20Maps/W2021/Main%20Trail%20Map%20Winter%2020-21.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;map of Big Sky, Montana&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A collection of Niehues&#39; &lt;a href=&#34;https://jamesniehues.com/collections/art/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;basemap art&lt;/a&gt; without labels, legends, etc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Acadia National Park (Maine)
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://npmaps.com/wp-content/uploads/acadia-map.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Main Park Map&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://npmaps.com/wp-content/uploads/acadia-isle-au-haut-map.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Isle au Haut Detail Map&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://npmaps.com/wp-content/uploads/acadia-context-map.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Regional Map&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Denali National Park (Alaska)
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://npmaps.com/wp-content/uploads/denali-map.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Main Park Map&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://npmaps.com/wp-content/uploads/denali-entrance-area-map.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Park Enterance Detail Map&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yellowstone National Park (Wyoming)
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://npmaps.com/wp-content/uploads/yellowstone-old-faithful-map.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Main Park Map&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nps.gov/carto/hfc/carto/media/YELLmap2.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Old Faithful Detail Map&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://npmaps.com/wp-content/uploads/yellowstone-regional-map.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Regional Map&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of the National Park Service maps are available via &lt;a href=&#34;http://npmaps.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;npmaps.com&lt;/a&gt;, which catalogs them because different parks make different types of maps available.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
